Finding Aid for Library Science Alumni Society (University of Michigan) records, 1936-1984
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Library Science Alumni Society (University of Michigan) records 1936-1984
University of Michigan. Library Science Alumni Society.
0.5 linear foot
87228 Bimu C646 2
Records, 1936-1984, of the Library Science Alumni Society of the University of Michigan. Includes constitutions, minutes of the Board of Directors (1942-1949) and Executive Committee (1950-1952 and 1977-1983), lists of officers and alumni, financial records, secretary's correspondence and material on the Library Science Anniversary Fund.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group came from the Society through Professor Kenneth Vance (donor no. 4855 ) in August 1984.
The record group is open without restriction.
The Library Science Alumni Society of the University of Michigan was founded in 1926. The Society established an annual student award in honor of Associate Professor Margaret Mann upon her retirement in 1938.
Records of the Library Science Alumni Society include constitutions, minutes of the Board of Directors (1942-1949) and Executive Committee (1950-1952 and 1977-1983), lists of officers and alumni, financial records, secretary's correspondence and material on the Library Science Anniversary Fund.
Subjects:
University of Michigan--Alumni and alumnae.; University of Michigan. School of Library Science.
- Records
  - Constitutions, 1936-1974 (Box 1)
  - Minutes
    - Board of Directors, 1942-1949 (Box 1)
    - Executive Committee, 1950-1952 and 1977-1983 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's Reports and Financial Information, 1962, 1965-1984 (Box 1)
  - Lists
    - Executive Board, 1973-984 (Box 1)
    - Past Presidents, 1936-1969 (Box 1)
    - Alumni officers and candidates and committee members, 1936-1960 (Box 1)
    - Life Members to 1968 (Box 1)
    - Charter Members (Box 1)
    - Alumni Directory, 1972-1978 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
  - Correspondence
    - William Bishop, University Librarian, 1935-1940 (Box 1)
    - Anna Clinger Smith, Assistant to William Bishop and Secretary of the Society, 1934-1949 (Box 1)
    - Letters from Alumni to Anna Smith, 1936-1945 (Box 1)
    - Marjory H. Drake, Secretary of the Society, 1949-1954 (Box 1)
    - Letters from Alumni to Marjory Drake, 1949-1954 (Box 1)
    - Mary Loughin, Secretary of the Society 1955-1968, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Kenneth Vance, Assistant Dean and Secretary-Treasurer (then Treasurer) of the Society, 1971-1982, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - Mass Mailings to Alumni (including Reports), 1936-1981 (Box 1)
      (scattered)
  - Material (including correspondence) for Alumni Notes, 1941-1959 (Box 1)
  - Programs and Announcements for Alumni in Residence Program and Other Events, 1973-1984 (Box 1)
  - Library Science 50th Anniversary Fund
    - Correspondence
      - David L. Reich, Chairman of Steering Committee, 1976-1978
        - General (Box 1)
        - Ashley, Patrick, President of Library Science Alumni Society (Box 1)
        - Bidlack, Russell, Dean of School of Library Science (Box 1)
        - Goodwin, Bill, Manager, School/College/Foundation Relations (Box 1)
        - Jacobs, Peter, Vice-President, Brodart, Inc. (Box 1)
        - Starring, Robert (Box 1)
        - Vance, Kenneth, Assistant Dean of School of Library Science (Box 1)
        - Williams, Glen, Associate Director, School and College Services (Box 1)
        - Sample Letters and Certificates (Box 1)
      - Bidlack, Russell, Dean, School of Library Science, 1976-1978 (Box 1)
      - Vance, Kenneth, Assistant Dean, School of Library Science, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
    - Endowed Chair Fund Drive Committee: Minutes, Memos, Financial Statements, and Membership Lists, 1976-1978 (Box 1)
    - Alumni Regional and Industry Chairpersons: Lists and Memos, 1976-1978 (Box 1)
    - Charter Members of the 50th Anniversary Club (Box 1)
    - 50th Anniversary Program, 1976 (Box 1)